Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair;
But I cannot sever the tangled threads on my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Mistress,
have you considered Dr. Wen's suggestion?
It wouldn't be a bad choice to ...
live a tranquil life with him.
Jinxi,
you know me the best.
Why would you test my intentions?
I will not be together with Wen Shichu.
My father is gravely ill and confined in Ningguta.
There is no one to take care of the whole Zhen clan.
What Yunli was able to do for me
is now my responsibility to carry alone.
Wen Shichu can't help me.
I have only myself to rely upon.
Yes, Mistress, since you have made up your mind,
you will not be alone.
Jade and I will always follow you.
But Mistress ...
What plan do you have in mind?
Yunli's death was suspicious ...
and I must not ignore it.
He told me before he left for Yunnan and Tibet
that the rebellious Dzungars often send spies to the area.
It's hard to tell ...
whether his accident
was vandalism or caused by Dzungar spies,
or even ...
someone related to the palace...
But whoever did it ...
I don't possess the ability to
revenge his death at the moment.
The child inside my belly
is destined to be born without a father.
But the bloodline of Noble Prince Guo
must be preserved.
This child ...
I must give him a rightful status
and properly raise him.
And my father...
I exercised restraint every step I took
only trying to protect my family.
But now my father ...
suddenly fell ill in Ningguta ...
I can't bear imagining him ...
Mistress,
there is only one person under heaven
who can help you achieve all this.
Correct.
Yunli told me that
His Majesty
called my name while he was unconscious.
I'm not entirely sure how ...
but I will do my utmost to ...
use His Majesty's hand
and his power
to take revenge.
Mistress,
this is the hardest and riskiest move.
Have you really thought this through?
There is no other path forward.
Yunli is already dead -
What is there to care about?
My body is an empty shell.
My Lady,
is your plan to reconcile with His Majesty?
If you meet His Majesty here,
I'm afraid that sooner than later
the harem would be alarmed
and someone would want to kill us.
Then we could only ...
sit here and wait for death.
We will return to the palace.
Dr. Wen.
Huan'er.
I look terrible, don't I?
No, why would you say that?
It's just that your qi and circulation have been poor,
which makes your skin look dull.
Insufficiency of qi and blood does no good to the baby inside me.
May I trouble you to prescribe some
herbs that will build my qi and blood?
Also,
do you still have the Immortal Jade Maiden Powder?
What do you need that powder for?
My Lady is determined to keep the child,
but how can the baby look well if My Lady is withered like this?
So she needs not only healthy foods and tonics,
but also the powder to improve her complexion.
I can't be happier to see you treating yourself well.
Make sure the herbs are quick acting ...
I hate seeing this haggard face.
I will.
Ejiao is very effective for replenishing qi
and enriching the blood.
I will prepare it and send it to Jinxi daily.
Please do nurse and nourish yourself.
Here, let me take your pulse.
Your pulse is smooth and strong.
All is well.
Huan'er, you must attend to yourself carefully.
Don't let sad emotions affect your qi.
The Imperial Infirmary might have tasks for me today.
I have to return to the palace now.
I will send the herbs as soon as possible.
Jinxi, please see Dr. Wen out.
Yes.
After you, Dr. Wen.
Don't tell him yet ...
about my plan to return to the palace.
Yes.
All I can do now is "adorn myself to please others".
You smell sweet.
Your Majesty always likes to tease me.
Why would I lie to you?
His Majesty went to the Palace of Prolonging Happiness again?
Yes, since His Majesty recovered,
he has been visiting Concubine An and Lady Paix the most.
There is no need to worry about Lady Paix,
but for Concubine An ...
Her Highness Concubine An seems obedient,
but her mind is not easy to predict.
What can she do when I don't allow her to have a baby?
Tell Spring to watch Consort An taking the
contraceptive tonics after every service
to avoid future troubles.
Yes.
Coua.
Go empty the censer quickly.
Yes.
Jinxi,
do you know anyone in the palace who
can influence His Majesty's opinion?
Su Peisheng is the only one who can do that for us.
He has been serving His Majesty since a young age
and knows His Majesty's temperament the best.
If you are planning a way to return to the palace,
you have to find a chance to meet His Majesty.
But we are not in the palace now.
I have nothing to exchange for Su Peisheng's help.
Not nothing, Mistress.
What hasn't Su Peisheng seen
through his life-long service to His Majesty?
Treasures or benefits might have little effect.
Then...
Su Peisheng is not physically complete.
Having no chance to start a family is
the deepest distress in his life.
That's why some eunuchs and maids in
the palace secretly become "eat-together partners“.
After all, "half a bowl is better than no rice at all."
Jinxi,
I won't allow you to do this for me.
This is our best option.
Su Peisheng and I are from the same hometown.
He helped me greatly when I first became
a maid in the harem.
Besides, after all these years...
he does still have some feelings towards me.
I'm willing to try my best.
Jinxi,
you've already endured too many ordeals living with me.
Now you are even going to...
become his "eat-together partner" for me.
I know it is common in the harem,
but after all, he is not a complete man...
Mistress,
I've thought this through
and I won't let you change my mind.
I said that
I would do anything for you
since you're determined to return to the palace.
Who knows about the future if we don't take the chance now?
If I'm lucky,
Su Peisheng will be the one I rely on all life long.
I will go get ready.
Where are you going?
Su Peisheng has a private residence outside the palace,
and I know its location.
I'm confident I'll find him there.
Jinxi, you truly don't need to do this for me.
We can find another way.
This is the best way.
Besides, your return to the palace does no harm to Su Peisheng.
If one day you regain His Majesty's favor,
Su Peisheng will only benefit from it.
With what little I am capable of,
we can make sure that it happens.
Don't worry, Mistress.
Jinxi?
It's you.
Someone, come here.
Yes.
Replace this with the tea His Majesty granted me.
You can drink mine first.
Thank you, Mr. Su.
You don't have to be so polite.
Make yourself at home.
Call me by my name.
Peisheng.
Sit down.
Your residence is newly refurbished...
How do you like it?
Not bad, it's just a little cold and quiet living here alone.
But I'm used to it after so many years.
Then...
Would it be too late if I say I want
to come here to accompany you?
So you...
You are finally saying yes to me?
You must have sore legs after
a whole day's work.
Life is composed of innumerable twists and turns.
But eventually,
everyone finds their way to the one they belong with.
It's just unfortunate that Concubine Sourire
will be alone and unattended.
I don't have the heart to see that happen.
Are you thinking ... Concubine Sourire and His Majesty...?
Do you suppose it could happen?
If Concubine Sourire still has a chance,
then that would allow us to also have a happy ending,
instead of disappointment.
At the moment, His Majesty lacks
a concubine he's deeply fond of.
But the Empress is dominant in the harem now.
As a banished concubine, I'm afraid it would be very difficult for
Concubine Sourire to re-enter the harem.
Whether it's difficult or not,
"people propose and Heaven disposes."
We can only do the best we can.
If one day His Majesty accepts Concubine Sourire's return,
then wouldn't it be natural for you and I to be together?
He's here.
Mr. Su.
Peace to Your Highness.
Sir, no need to bow. Have a seat.
- I thank Your Highness.
- Jade, the tea.
Please sit.
I am no longer a Concubine.
You shouldn't address me like that, sir.
I have my own reasons to address Your Highness that way.
I don't quite understand what you mean by that.
Jinxi came to me the other day.
She didn't say much, but I was able to guess some of it.
Now that I see Your Highness's radiant
complexion despite living in a temple,
I am more certain of how things stand.
Then sir, what brought you here today?
I am here to congratulate Your Highness
that your wish will come true.
Why do you say that?
Your Highness,
I have attended His Majesty for many years.
I am somewhat able to fathom how His Majesty thinks.
If it were not for Your Highness's refusal to
bend to His Majesty's will at that time,
how would His Majesty have had the heart
to let you leave the palace?
Otherwise, Your Highness would have
been ranked a Consort now, right?
There's no need to talk of the past.
What does Your Highness mean?
I willfully insisted on leaving the palace.
But my family was convicted -
I no longer have the standing to serve His Majesty.
Since leaving the palace I've missed His Majesty very much.
Mr. Su, I hope you can impart
my thoughts and feelings to His Majesty.
Yes.
Your Highness was sent to the
Temple of Pure Dew by His Majesty's decree.
Then, Your Highness moved here.
I can surmise that Your Highness must
have endured unfair treatment at the temple.
Living in such desolate quarters in the mountains ...
must have caused much suffering to Your Highness.
There's nothing to be afraid of from material hardship.
I'm only afraid of the unhappiness in my heart.
If I had a chance to see His Majesty
and the princess once again in my life,
I would be able to rest in peace when I die.
I am thankful for the good graces
Your Highness bestowed on me in the past.
I will do my utmost.
Please rise.
Nothing is constant in this world.
I'm afraid His Majesty already has
new concubines by his side
and has long forgotten me.
Your Highness should not say so.
If I didn't have some confidence,
I wouldn't have come to see Your Highness so suddenly.
By that, sir, do you mean you already have a good plan?
Since Your Highness left the harem,
His Majesty has always had you in his heart.
However, as the Emperor, His Majesty
will not bend his head and give in to Your Highness.
Your Highness has a brilliant mind and
will understand if you think it through.
If it weren't for His Majesty's implicit approval,
even if the Empress Dowager allowed it,
how could Madam Orchid have visited
Your Highness so frequently over the past years?
When His Majesty was sick in the past,
he called out no one's name other than Empress Première's.
Your Highness was the first exception.
The Empress Dowager was present that day.
It surprised Her Majesty greatly.
This shows His Majesty's enduring affection for Your Highness,
which matters very much.
To tell the truth,
State Prince Guo was present as well.
He heard His Majesty saying this in his sleep.
Unfortunately, His Lordship won't be coming back anymore.
How is it that His Lordship is not coming back?
That's meant to remain secret in the palace.
I shouldn't have mentioned it.
His Majesty does not intend to announce his death.
How sad.
State Prince Guo's bloodline ended so abruptly.
Your Highness must be tired.
Please have some water before you continue.
His Lordship was young.
This is so unfortunate.
That's certainly true.
Aiyo, we've been busy talking about others.
In fact, if Your Highness wishes to see His Majesty -
That's not impossible.
A couple of days ago, we were discussing
the incense offering and spring hike
for the Longtaitou Festival on the
second day of the second month.
I will try my best to convince His Majesty
to offer incense at the Temple of Pure Dew.
At that time, I will prompt His Majesty
to come to Peak Lingyun.
Thank you for the trouble, Mr. Su.
It is not... an easy task.
I appreciate you making such an effort.
It's not necessarily very difficult.
Please allow me to think of a way.
Mr. Su.
I really don't know how to repay your kindness at this time.
Your Highness ...
I am helping Your Highness
and also helping myself.
I will send someone if there is anything to report.
Allow me to take my leave now.
Jade, please send Mr. Su on his way.
No need, please stay.
It's all right, Mistress. Allow me to accompany him.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Take this, I brought some funds for you.
But...
Take it. Xiao-Xiazi is there.
I will have some fabric sent here in a couple of days.
The clothes you are wearing now
look like they're from a few years ago.
You should have new clothing.
I'm leaving now.
Let's head back.
Yes.
- Come, Princess!
- Slow down！
Come!
Be careful!
His Majesty the Emperor.
Peace to Your Majesty.
You may rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
I just visited Imperial Mother.
She still looks unwell.
I heard that you've been taking care of her.
It is only my duty to attend to Her Majesty.
Rise.
Your Majesty, the weather is so nice.
Concubine Vertu has brought the Princess out
to "set foot on spring grass."
Indeed.
In a few days, it will be Longtaitou Festival.
[Dragon Raises its Head Festival]
The tradition is to do a spring hike
and incense offering.
Does Your Majesty want to offer prayers
at Baohua Hall as usual?
I've been at the Baohua Hall every year,
never stepping outside the palace.
What kind of spring hike is that?
I heard that people in the capital go out
for a trip and attend temple fairs.
They do.
If so,
I'd rather stay at the Hall of Mental
Cultivation to read my memorandums.
Your Majesty,
Longtaitou is a big festival.
As the saying goes:
"The day the dragon raises its head,
come the blessings for plentiful crops."
This is the best day to pray for favorable winds and rains.
Your Majesty shouldn't let it pass by.
On this day, the people love to worship
the Flower God to welcome the spring,
which makes the Flower God Temple
the busiest place of all.
I was sweating all over last year
amidst the huge crowds of people.
My toe was almost crushed even!
Does Your Majesty want to go there...?
The crowd is too noisy.
I don't want to join in the bustle.
I was thinking if we put the trip together with
the blessing and the incense offering,
I could suggest a suitable place.
Your Majesty, I remember when I was little,
the spring view on Peak Lingyun was lushly beautiful.
And then Your Majesty could visit the Temple of Pure Dew
to pray and offer incense.
That would be only a one day trip.
Yes exactly, Your Highness.
I was just about to mention that place.
This is the best time for spring scenery
at the Temple of Pure Dew.
And it's a quiet place for a leisurely walk.
Since the temple belongs to the Imperial Family,
there will be fewer people.
The Temple of Pure Dew.
I understand
there's someone Your Majesty doesn't want to see.
We are just offering incense there.
We don't need to see her.
Also, we can pray for Her Majesty
the Empress Dowager's health at the temple.
It will show more sincerity.
If it's still early,
I will accompany Your Majesty for a walk at Peak Lingyun.
Since the people are all going out
on the second day of the second month...
Might as well.
I will take the opportunity to see
the different facets of people's lives.
Yes, Your Majesty, I will arrange it right away.
Imperial Father.
Your Highness, I heard that on the
second day of the second month,
His Majesty is going out to
pray for the Empress Dowager.
Out of the palace? To where?
The Temple of Pure Dew.
He shouldn't...
I have asked around.
Zhen Huan caught tuberculosis and
was evicted to Peak Lingyun.
She's not at the Temple of Pure Dew.
That's good then.
Tell them to keep an eye out
and make sure His Majesty returns early.
Yes.
Su Peisheng is very thoughtful.
I assume these clothes were rushed
and completed overnight in my size.
These satin pieces are for you.
Look at these colors and patterns -
They are what you usually like.
Yes, they are,
but good or bad, this is my fate.
What?
I like them, Mistress.
Su Peisheng's head attendant said
you should dress up, Mistress.
These gifts indicate it.
I understand Su Peisheng's message.
He wants me to be well-dressed, to
immediately win over His Majesty's heart.
But this would appear to be deliberate.
The other day, when Su Peisheng spoke about
how much His Majesty cares about you, Mistress,
it was really touching.
Is it really deep affection?
The one who takes a person as the shadow of another
only hurts himself and others.
His Majesty treats everyone with a cold heart.
The so-called care and affection
bestowed by a cold-hearted person...
Jinxi, could you be touched by that?
But the moment Su Peisheng mentioned it,
I noticed your eyebrow moving slightly.
Mistress, have any feelings of affection
crossed your mind?
Isn't it pointless
to accept a feeble medicine
when every inch of me has been injured?
Pointless or not,
as long as His Majesty has this feeling,
we can succeed with half the effort.
Your Majesty, please have some tea.
Where is Concubine Sourire from the palace?
Your Majesty,
Concubine Sourire has moved to the living quarters
at Peak Lingyun due to her illness.
She's sick...?
For how long? How serious?
I guess...
Concubine Sourire should be better now.
Ridiculous!
What do you mean by "should be better now"?
You are the abbess. How can you not know?
Tell me,
How is it that she arrived healthy,
but fell sick here?
I...
We beg Your Majesty's forgiveness.
It is our greatest honor to have
Concubine Sourire here to practice Buddhism.
Yes.
Everyone in the temple respects and admires her
without the slightest insolence!
But Concubine Sourire harbors Buddha's
great compassion and benevolence.
She refused to trouble others
and insisted on doing everything by herself.
She helped the senior and weak nuns
wash clothes, chop wood and carry water.
Yes. Yes.
Concubine Sourire was not in very good health,
and one day she didn't withstand the cold and fell ill.
Indeed.
You say she washed clothes, chopped wood and carried water?
Yes. Yes.
How is she now?
Your Majesty,
we provided Concubine Sourire separate
living quarters for her recovery.
I believe she should have recovered now.
Yes.
Lead me to the living quarters.
Yes, Your Majesty.
My Lady, combing your hair with jasmine water
leaves every strand a light scent of jasmine flowers.
It smells really good.
I hope this light floral scent
won't displease anyone.
My Lady, I'm scared...
I'm worried that you won't succeed today...
And if you succeed,
I'm afraid the road ahead will be even more perilous.
But I don't have
any other path in front of me.
My Lady, your monastic robe looks very plain and modest.
Why not dress more nicely since you've made up your mind?
In the palace, His Majesty has seen every color,
both bright and subdued.
I will remain pure and natural.
After all, we are practicing Buddhism.
Any adornment would seem inappropriate in the mountain.
This is just right.
It's His Majesty's procession.
How extravagant.
Namo Amitābha.
Mistress, you didn't sleep well again last night.
How about ...
Your Majesty!
His Majesty?
How could His Majesty be here...
Mistress, it's really His Majesty.
I did not lie to you!
Huan Huan...
I just now heard from the nuns
that Concubine Sourire moved here due to illness
but should have recovered by now.
Why do you still look unwell to me?
Your Majesty, it's also my first time to visit here.
I don't know why Prioress Mochou...
Concubine Sourire is still ill.
What did you say just now?
Concubine Sourire didn't sleep well again?
Why did you say "again"?
Your Majesty,
Mistress was relocated because
they insisted she had tuberculosis.
We left on a frozen and snowy day.
Mistress was weak, and her illness worsened.
In reality, it wasn't tuberculosis at all.
It's because My Lady wasn't nursed well
in the first month after giving birth.
She was persistently coughing.
That's how the chronic symptoms developed.
We thought taking medicine would help
cure her illness in the spring.
But since leaving the palace,
Mistress missed Your Majesty and the Princess so much.
She was often so distracted she couldn't sleep well,
the result was that she never fully recovered.
Ask them all to back off.
Stay out! Out!
You all will wait down there.
Not even a fly is allowed to pass by!
And listen,
if anyone dares to speak a word,
they are forsaking their own head!
Is that understood?
Yes.
- You may go.
- Go, quickly.
His Majesty...
His Majesty is accompanied by Her Highness. Leave now!
Yes, yes.
Huan Huan, I’m here. I’m here.
Si Lang.
I have been waiting for you for so long.
You make my heart hurt.
Si Lang.
How is this going?
“Once the canal is built, the river will flow.”
I didn't expect it to go so smoothly.
They both have feelings for each other.
"The drum beats a rhythm and the instruments fit in."
Just wait for the happy result!
Let’s go.
Why are you crying?
Everyone said that I was incorrigibly wrong
when I insisted on leaving the palace.
Only I knew then,
and I still know now,
there was ...
nothing wrong with my decision that day.
I used to think Si Lang
had lost all affection for me.
And that you asked me to stay in the palace
only because I bear some resemblance to Empress Première,
and because I gave birth to Longyue.
I adore you so much, Si Lang.
I was really hurt when you wrote to Empress Première
“Sourire resembles you.”
Why would you talk about this now?
Si Lang.
I have been thinking continuously since I left the palace:
If Si Lang still has any true affection towards me,
no, even if the slightest trace of it,
I could die without regret.
I have been away for three years now, Si Lang.
Although we haven't seen each other for three years,
Si Lang, you still have me on your mind.
When Your Majesty said you came to Peak Lingyun
because you heard I was ill and relocated...
As long as I know that Si Lang still has a sincere heart for me,
there will be no regret over these three years apart.
I would have given ten years off my life
if only I could have known sooner.
I don't allow you to say that.
Huan Huan.
Three years at the Temple of Pure Dew
has softened your temperament a lot.
If you weren’t so headstrong at the time,
acting on your emotions,
how could I have had the heart to let you leave the palace?
Three days after you gave birth to Longyue,
I abolished your rank and title
so you could reflect on your mistakes.
Had you held your rank and title,
how would you have experienced the
hardship of life outside the palace?
None of that matters now.
I just want Si Lang here.
Si Lang.
I was afraid I would never see you again in my life.
And Longyue,
our Longyue...
Longyue has grown up very well.
You have no idea how adorable she is,
and how much Consort Estime adores her.
It's unfortunate that I can't bring her here to visit you.
I've been plagued by illness.
The hardships I have endured here
are karmic retribution for my willful acts in the past.
Although I have left the Forbidden City,
all those I have in my heart
reside in the Forbidden City.
Whenever Madam Orchid comes to visit me,
I don't even have the courage to ask about Si Lang.
I'm afraid she will tell me
you have new concubines by your side
and have completely forgotten about me.
Every day, I can only chant the sutra a hundred times,
praying for your and Longyue's happiness and good health.
It is already a blessing of my entire life
for me to see my Si Lang again.
You have already learned your lesson.
If you hadn't been away for three years,
I would have never known how much I would yearn for you.
Si Lang, your affection is deep and profound.
It makes me so ashamed;
No place I could stand would tolerate my existence.
Did you know
how much has happened in the palace these years?
I don't have anyone I can speak my heart with.
After you left,
I visited the Palace of Pearl Jade once.
Except for Endless Longing, the Zither,
you didn't take anything else with you.
You even left this hairpin on the dresser.
Endless Longing was given to me personally
by Your Majesty.
Aside from my feelings of longing,
everything else
was a worldly possession I could leave behind.
Huan Huan.
I ordered you to cease ornamentation and become a nun.
Today, would you be willing to adorn yourself for me again?
Si Lang, I am willing to do anything you wish.
I only have one request.
I am already a banished concubine.
It is my greatest fortune to be able
to serve Your Majesty again.
I don't wish what happened today
to cause disputes among the concubines.
You are still seeing yourself as a banished concubine?
Did you notice what I called you in front of
Su Peisheng and Cui Jinxi?
Huan Huan,
in all these years you have never left my heart.
You
have always been Concubine Sourire to me.
If you don't want to stir up trouble in the palace,
then
I won't even speak of this to the Empress.
I will have Su Peisheng take care of your
everyday needs from now on.
As long as Si Lang has me in his heart,
even a bitterly lonesome life here
would be as sweet as honey.
Huan Huan, I would never allow you to live
a lonely life given how perceptive and thoughtful you are.
Since the Empress Dowager
still hasn't recovered from her illness,
I will order the Temple of Pure Dew to hold
a praying ceremony once a month.
I will come here to offer incense personally.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.